Keith Frazier

Full Stack Developer

keithfrazier98@gmail.com • 909-240-6327 • www.keithfrazier.me

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 3 years as a Full Stack Developer with a small blockchain startup

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, GraphQL, Node.js, React

Vercel, Heroku, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio, Postman, Adobe Illustrator

Methodologies Test Driven Development, Mobile First Design, Pair Programming, Kanban, Scrum

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hashmesh Labs

Remote

Full Stack Developer

09/2021 - 09/2022

Technologies: TypeScript, Node.js, GraphQL, Express, React, Tailwind, Jest, Puppeteer, HTML, CSS, Vercel

- Collaborated on 2 production applications, 4 startup web apps, 2 JavaScript libraries, and 2 REST APIs
- Created a gateway API that decreased queries and endpoints on the front end by 5 times
- Integrated Google Analytics into 2 applications
- Responsible for managing CI/CD pipeline and deployment, as well as NPM version updates
- Implemented end to end testing on front end applications, and unit + integration tests on libraries and APIs

Montclair Bronze Montclair, California

Computer Numerical Control Programmer

09/2019 - 08/2020

Technologies: G-code, Autodesk Fusion 360, CNC technology

- Created 3D models from 2D blueprints for over 20 production parts
- Optimized programs to be on average 25% faster with generated toolpaths instead of legacy handwritten code
- Organized anonymous directories into intelligible file structures, reducing duplicate code by over 40%
- Trained new employees on machine operation and setup

2016-2019: Worked in composite and metal manufacturing. Certified machinist for 2 years. Learned leadership and collaboration skills.

PROJECTS

Periodic Tables

07/2021 - Current

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Express, Node, Vercel, Heroku-Postgres

- Built a proof of concept web app to manage tables and reservations for a restaurant as a bootcamp capstone
- GitHub: https://github.com/keithfrazier98/periodic-tables-monorepo

GrubDash 06/2021 - Current

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, React, Express, Jest, Vercel

- Built an API for food delivery applications to get and create data for user orders and restaurant meals.
- GitHub: https://github.com/keithfrazier98/grubdash-api

EDUCATION & ACCREDITATIONS

Thinkful 01/2021 - 07/2021

- Learned industry-standard languages, frameworks, libraries, and methodologies
- Studied data structures and algorithms, asymptotic analysis, and Big O notation